Preliminary Guide to the Milton C. Marney papers, 1908-2003 RL.00849
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Milton C. Marney papers
1908-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marney, Milton C.
RL.00849
9.6 Linear Feet
Scientist, taxonomist, and brother of Carlyle Marney. Collection contains professional and personal correspondence including family letters. Also included are research papers and book chapters on taxonomy and prescriptive science.
7,200 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Milton C. Marney papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006.
Biographical Note
Scientist, taxonomist, and brother of Carlyle Marney.
Collection Overview
Collection contains professional and personal correspondence including family letters. Also included are research papers and book chapters on taxonomy and prescriptive science.
Related Material
Marney, Carlyle, 1916-. Papers, 1899-1979 & 1958-1978. (bulk) [manuscript]
Duke University
Management science; Photographs; Science -- Philosophy; Marney, Carlyle, 1916-1978; Marney, Milton C.; Marney, Milton C.
- Accession, 2006 (2006-0134), 16 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Collection contains professional and personal correspondence including family letters. Also included are research papers and book chapters on taxonomy and prescriptive science.
  - Correspondence - personal, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Academic papers (Box 1)
  - Typescripts and manuscripts of poetry (Box 1)
  - Music manuscripts (Box 1)
  - Research files (Box 2)
  - E-mail correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - personal, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Typescripts and manuscripts of poetry (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - personal, 1968, 1976-1977 (Box 3)
  - Research files (Box 3)
  - Carlyle Marney typescripts (Box 4)
  - Research files (Box 4)
  - Correspondence - professsional, 1959-1962 (Box 4)
  - Carlyle Marney typescripts (Box 5)
  - Research typescripts (Box 5)
  - Covers for Scientific American, 1949-1954 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - professional (Box 5)
  - Research typescripts - AiResearch Manufacturing Company, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Academic papers - college work, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Typescript: Nonproliferation Alternative System Assessment Program, U.S. Department of Energy: Public Concerns and Alternative Nuclear Power Systems, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Typescript: The World Institute Council: Fields Within Fields Within Fields…, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
  - Academic typescripts - magazine articles, 1948, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - professional, 1976-1979 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - personal, 1941-1978 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - professional, 1969-1978 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - personal, 1938-1954 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - professional, 1948-1971 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with Emily Rushworth, 1945-1986 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with Sarah Victoria, 1949-1968 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with Evelyn, 1968-1976 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence with Carlyle Marney (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with Virginia Robinson (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with A. Hassanein, 1972-1976 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence with Sarah Victoria and Evelyn, 1968-1970 (Box 9)
  - General personal correspondence (Box 9)
  - General professional correspondence (Box 9)
  - Correspondence from Elizabeth and Carlyle Marney (Box 10)
  - Research typescripts, 1964, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence with Evelyn, 1932-1989 (Box 10)
  - Academic papers - schoolwork from David, Matthew, Nathan, and Stephen Marney, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Research typescripts, 1961-1978 (Box 11)
  - Typescript - The World Institute Council: Fields Within Fields Within Fields…, 1973-1974 (Box 11)
  - Resume, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Research typescripts - Research Analysis Corporation, 1961-1969 (Box 11)
  - Typescripts of poetry - Poems by Milton Marney, 1982 (Box 11)
  - Research typescripts: originals of Research Analysis Corporation research on value theory and prescripting sciences, 1960-1971 (Box 12)
  - Research manuscripts and typescripts - social ecosystems, 1976-1978 (Box 12)
  - Typescript - Emergent Features of Scientific Advance by Milton Marney and Paul F. Schmidt, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Research typescripts - interdisciplinary systems, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Research manuscripts and typescripts - Implications of bio-medical and behavioral research, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - Research proposals, 1974 (Box 12)
  - Research typescripts - general (Box 12)
  - Draft of Foundations of the Prescriptive Sciences by Nicholas M. Smith and Milton C. Marney, Volumes I and II, 1972 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - personal (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - personal (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - personal (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - Sadie and Leonard: personal letters, 1908-1910 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence - personal (Box 16)